<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RPN on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/tags/rpn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RPN on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rpn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RPNs have a strong voice with CUPE</title>
      <link>/facts/rpn-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/rpn-info/</guid>
      <description>New infographic flyer explains why CUPE is the right union for RPNs.
Download the PDF version
CUPE bargaining sets the lead for all hospital service, RPN, and clerical workers in Ontario. Comparing our collective agreements to other unions bears this out. CUPE has superior language on seniority rights, job security, layoffs and recall, and health and safety to name but a few issues.
Did you know that?  With nearly 80,000 members employed in hospitals, long-term care, community care and paramedicine, CUPE is Ontario’s largest health care union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nursing News</title>
      <link>/newsletter/nurse-june19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 16:43:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/newsletter/nurse-june19/</guid>
      <description>Nursing Graduate Guarantee Programme Changes Changes made to the Nursing Graduate Guarantee Programme in April concern CUPE because it more strongly encourages the hiring into full-time positions of nurses who have just graduated from community college.
Many RPNs work part-time for years waiting to acquire the seniority to post successfully into a full-time position with benefits.
Th real problem the Ministry of Health needs to address are the budget cuts to Ontario Hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>