<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Twh on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/tags/twh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Twh on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:47:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/twh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time and casual clerical staff at Toronto Western Hospital choose CUPE</title>
      <link>/news/twh-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/twh-victory/</guid>
      <description>TORONTO, ON – Over 100 part-time and casual clerical staff at Toronto Western Hospital have chosen to improve their working conditions and increase their job security by joining the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE).
Workers cited the need for a fair and equal staffing process, predictable and consistent scheduling, job security, and an end to working full-time hours on casual contracts that lack benefits and protection, as the primary motivations for unionizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clerical News - July</title>
      <link>/newsletter/clerical-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 16:43:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/newsletter/clerical-july/</guid>
      <description>Technological changes pose particular issues for clerical staff Below are just some examples of the revolution through technological change taking place in hospitals across Ontario, which is eliminating the jobs of clerical employees.
 Digitization of medical records Automation of dicta-typing and medical transcription Electronic patient registration kiosks  In our central bargaining with Ontario hospitals, CUPE is seeking increased protections against the impact of technological changes on clerical staff.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>