<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hospital on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/hospital/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hospital on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/hospital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Providence Hospital</title>
      <link>/hospital/providence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hospital/providence/</guid>
      <description>CUPE Local 1590 has represented employees at Providence Healthcare since 1973. Since then the Local has expanded to include employees of DTZ who also work at Providence Healthcare as well as employees at Hazelton Retirement Residence. Currently the membership includes 700 fulltime, part time and casual workers.
Hospital workers have seen more than our share of change in the workplace. Hospital mergers similar to the one between the Providence and St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>St. Michael&#39;s Hospital</title>
      <link>/hospital/stmikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hospital/stmikes/</guid>
      <description>Joining CUPE A process is underway to determine the appropriate bargaining units and respective unions that will represent workers in the newly merged “Our Shared Purpose” hospital network.
Before a vote is called, the Labour Board, the employer and the unions must first determine the following: number and structure of bargaining units in the merged hospital; what positions will be included; and which unions will be on each ballot. The next mediation date is scheduled for June 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto Western Hospital</title>
      <link>/hospital/twh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hospital/twh/</guid>
      <description>CUPE Welcomes TWH Part-Time &amp;amp; Clerical Congratulations for voting to join CUPE!
An overwhelming majority of part-time and casual clerical at TWH have voted in favour of joining CUPE.
Next steps: Over the next few weeks CUPE will be contacting you and setting-up a membership meeting to answer all your questions.
At this meeting we will also be discussing:
 options of establishing your own local or joining another local in the UHN Network your bargaining priorities electing officers outlining the way forward to getting a collective agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>