<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:47:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto hospital workers call on employer to show respect and implement the contract they negotiated</title>
      <link>/news/implement-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/implement-contract/</guid>
      <description>Workers at St. Joseph’s Health Centre and Providence Healthcare are rallying to demand that their employer implement the collective agreement that was negotiated and ratified in May. The contract includes new provisions to protect workers from violence in the workplace and wage increases retroactive to September 2017.
Our Shared Purpose is the name of the Catholic hospital network created from the merger of St. Michael’s Hospital, St. Joseph’s Health Centre and Providence Health Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part-time and casual clerical staff at Toronto Western Hospital choose CUPE</title>
      <link>/news/twh-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/twh-victory/</guid>
      <description>TORONTO, ON – Over 100 part-time and casual clerical staff at Toronto Western Hospital have chosen to improve their working conditions and increase their job security by joining the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE).
Workers cited the need for a fair and equal staffing process, predictable and consistent scheduling, job security, and an end to working full-time hours on casual contracts that lack benefits and protection, as the primary motivations for unionizing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUPE will now represent over 1,900 staff at Kingston Health Sciences Centre</title>
      <link>/news/kingston-victory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 20:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/kingston-victory/</guid>
      <description>CUPE victory in Kingston merger vote More than 1,900 Kingston Health Sciences Centre (KHSC) staff have voted to be represented by CUPE, Canada’s largest health care union.
Clerical staff, registered practical nurses and care aides, porters, dietary, environmental, trades and other services staff at both KHSC sites (Kingston General Hospital and Hotel Dieu Hospital) took part in a workplace representation vote at the end of last week supervised by the Ontario Labour Relations Board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have reached a settlement in CUPE central hospital bargaining</title>
      <link>/news/central-agreement-2018-04-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/central-agreement-2018-04-25/</guid>
      <description>The Ontario Council of Hospital Unions (OCHU) is the hospital division CUPE. OCHU/CUPE bargains a provincial collective agreement with the Ontario Hospital Association and lays that pattern down across the hospital sector and for those long-term care facilities that have a relationship with a hospital. CUPE bargaining sets the lead for all hospital service, RPN, and clerical workers in Ontario. Comparing our collective agreements to other unions bears this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kingston, Southeastern Ontario hospital staff join province-wide rallies April 18</title>
      <link>/news/workingtogether-2018-04-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/workingtogether-2018-04-17/</guid>
      <description>Hospital workers from Kingston and other southeastern Ontario communities will be demonstrating along with their counterparts at hospitals across the province Wednesday, April 18 at noon.
The rallies are the second in a series of escalating actions that 75,000 hospital workers, who are without a contract, are taking part in this April. It is rare for hospital workers to “visibly” protest in this way around their own contract negotiations.
CUPE, SEIU Healthcare and Unifor have formed an alliance and are mobilizing together to push Ontario hospitals to treat the hospital workers they represent with respect at the bargaining table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUPE Coordinating with Other Healthcare Unions for Provincial Contract</title>
      <link>/news/unions-together-2018-03-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/unions-together-2018-03-28/</guid>
      <description>The Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE), along with other unions, is trying to negotiate a provincial contract on behalf of the 35000 nurses, personal support workers, porters, administrative staff and dietary, cleaning and trades staff in Ontario.
The unique and historic meeting of three healthcare unions brought together delegations from local unions and leaders from the three unions to discuss a joint strategy for bargaining. Local union leaders are meeting and voting on several motions to support a joint campaign to mobilize against the hospitals’ demands for concessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaplains and spiritual care practitioners from three Toronto hospitals vote to unionize</title>
      <link>/news/chaplains-2018-03-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/chaplains-2018-03-20/</guid>
      <description>TORONTO, ON – Chaplains and spiritual Care Practitioners from St. Joseph’s Health Centre, Providence Health Centre and St. Michael’s Hospitals have joined the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE) in a certification vote held Monday afternoon. The thirty-two person unit consists of hospital chaplains and spiritual care practitioners from different religious denominations across the three hospitals, which merged in 2017 and are now collectively known as Our Shared Purpose. Spiritual Care has been integral to these hospitals since their foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring the Facts at St. Mike&#39;s</title>
      <link>/news/stmikes-2017-12-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/stmikes-2017-12-03/</guid>
      <description>Dear CUPE supporter, We’ve heard from many of you about the misinformation and confusion spread by HR in a series of “info sessions” held last week. We would like to restore some facts into the discussion:
 CUPE absolutely can and will protect against layoffs. Our hospital collective agreements have the strongest job security provisions in the industry. CUPE members are entitled to: 5 months notice in advance of layoffs, retraining for other positions within the hospital, bumping rights, recall rights from a layoff to an available opening and layoff benefits and separation allowances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUPE Anti-Violence Campaign News</title>
      <link>/news/violence-news-2017-11-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/violence-news-2017-11-16/</guid>
      <description>CUPE/OCHU&amp;rsquo;s anti-violence campaign Epidemic of Violence received extensive media coverage. The media reported on the polling and stories of physical attacks, sexual harassment, verbal abuse, and violence in Ontario hospitals.
Every day, frontline caregivers are suffering serious injuries that lead to time off work and even post-traumatic stress disorder. Instead of protecting their staff, hospital managers discourage them from reporting incidents and have even fired a nurse for revealing the real epidemic of violence in healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-union clerical are affected by the merger at St. Mike&#39;s: CUPE Podcast</title>
      <link>/news/merger-update1-2017-11-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/merger-update1-2017-11-05/</guid>
      <description>Podcast explaining the effect of the merger process at St. Mike&amp;rsquo;s on non-union clerical.
Listen to the podcast here.
Hello CUPE supporters!
As you may be aware, there has been a merger between Providence, St. Joseph’s and St. Michael’s hospitals as of August 1, 2017.
With any public sector merger such as this, there are government regulations that guide the process. When merging workplaces with many unions, there must be a vote by the workers to select a single union to represent the newly merged workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>150 Kingston hospital staff push for better hospital funding at large Ottawa rally Friday</title>
      <link>/news/kingston-funding-2017-10-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/kingston-funding-2017-10-27/</guid>
      <description>Click here to read the Kingston Whig-Standard article on the rally by Ian MacAlpine.
CUPE PRESS RELEASE KINGSTON, ON – More than 150 hospital staff from Kingston Health Sciences Centre KHSC), represented by the Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE 1974) will board several buses early Friday (October 27, 2017) morning and head to Ottawa. There, they will join hundreds of other hospital workers from across Ontario, for a noon rally at Ottawa’s Montfort Hospital, calling for better provincial funding for hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCHU/CUPE launch anti-violence at work campaign: Epidemic of Violence</title>
      <link>/news/violence-campaign-2017-09-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 09:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/violence-campaign-2017-09-12/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Ontario hospitals don&amp;rsquo;t want you to know that violence against hospital staff is real and rampant,&amp;rdquo; says union taking public awareness campaign to radio today
 Media Release
October 17, 2017
TORONTO, ON - A small investment in a Plexiglass barrier would have prevented a patient from stabbing a Perth/Smiths Falls hospital admitting clerk in the neck. Better alarms would have enabled nurses at Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s St. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s Health Centre to summon help when a patient, asked to take his medication, became violent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Hospitals Cooking</title>
      <link>/news/hosptial-cooking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/hosptial-cooking/</guid>
      <description>St. Joseph’s Health Centre is in the process of making a decision about how to prepare and deliver food in its cafeteria.
Rather than serve “TV dinner” style food from a factory operation outside of Toronto, we think the hospital should consider patient well-being and the needs of the community.
We are calling on St. Joseph’s to:  Serve food that is cooked in-house Use good quality, fresh ingredients Use locally sourced, organic food when possible Focus on patient well-being, not cutting corners  There is a local food solution Parkdale is already home to a local food movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To all non-union employees of UHN</title>
      <link>/news/uhn-letter-2017-08-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/uhn-letter-2017-08-29/</guid>
      <description>Recently you received a letter from UHN in response to CUPE’s organizing drive. The letter you received contained some inaccuracies and outdated information. In this letter, you will find updated and accurate information regarding CUPE and unions in general.
The first issue that needs to be addressed is regarding the Ontario Liberal Government’s net zero bargaining policy. The government officially ended their net zero policy in the fall of 2016 after it began to fall apart thanks to union contract settlements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 hospital funding well below average, bad news for Kingston patient care, say care staff</title>
      <link>/news/kingston-2007-08-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/kingston-2007-08-02/</guid>
      <description>MEDIA RELEASE, August 2, 2017
KINGSTON, ON — Below average provincial funding of about 1.4 per cent for the newly amalgamated Kingston Health Sciences Centre (KHSC) in 2017, “is bad news for patient care and cause for alarm at a time of significant change,” said Canadian Union of Public Employees (CUPE) 1974 president Mike Rodrigues at a media conference today.
A general 3.1 per cent increase in hospital funding was proposed in the 2017 provincial budget last April.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your right to join a union is protected by law in Ontario.</title>
      <link>/news/union-rights-2016-01-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/union-rights-2016-01-01/</guid>
      <description>The Ontario Labour Relations Act (OLRA) In Ontario the OLRA protects the rights of workers to join a Union. Sections 70 and 72 of the OLRA prohibit employers from interfering with an employee’s right to join a union and ensures that employees are free from coercion, intimidation, threats, promises or undue influence, including reprisals for their support and involvement with the union. If the employer violates those rights CUPE will file an Unfair Labour Practice application with the Labour Board.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>