<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Providence on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/tags/providence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Providence on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:47:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/providence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Toronto hospital workers call on employer to show respect and implement the contract they negotiated</title>
      <link>/news/implement-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/implement-contract/</guid>
      <description>Workers at St. Joseph’s Health Centre and Providence Healthcare are rallying to demand that their employer implement the collective agreement that was negotiated and ratified in May. The contract includes new provisions to protect workers from violence in the workplace and wage increases retroactive to September 2017.
Our Shared Purpose is the name of the Catholic hospital network created from the merger of St. Michael’s Hospital, St. Joseph’s Health Centre and Providence Health Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We have reached a settlement in CUPE central hospital bargaining</title>
      <link>/news/central-agreement-2018-04-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/central-agreement-2018-04-25/</guid>
      <description>The Ontario Council of Hospital Unions (OCHU) is the hospital division CUPE. OCHU/CUPE bargains a provincial collective agreement with the Ontario Hospital Association and lays that pattern down across the hospital sector and for those long-term care facilities that have a relationship with a hospital. CUPE bargaining sets the lead for all hospital service, RPN, and clerical workers in Ontario. Comparing our collective agreements to other unions bears this out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonization: What is the process?</title>
      <link>/facts/harmonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/harmonization/</guid>
      <description>What is Harmonization? Harmonization is the process of taking the Collective Agreements from all the union’s involved in the merger, along with any non union working conditions, and merging them into the new ‘first’ Collective Agreement.
Some employers see a merger as an opportunity to table concessions to Collective Agreements or non union working conditions but CUPE negotiates to maintain superior conditions and believes that you should not lose hard won rights and benefits due to a merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Posting and Promotion Update for newly merged hospitals</title>
      <link>/facts/post-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/post-promotion/</guid>
      <description>What should I do if I hold a position at more than one location? Nothing! The employer has advised CUPE that they will not be making any changes at this time, even if you are working more than the Full time Equivalent or max hours in the collective agreement.
Human Resources as advised all their managers of this so no one should be advised by their manager or supervisor that they need to resign from any position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUPE Anti-Violence Campaign News</title>
      <link>/news/violence-news-2017-11-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/violence-news-2017-11-16/</guid>
      <description>CUPE/OCHU&amp;rsquo;s anti-violence campaign Epidemic of Violence received extensive media coverage. The media reported on the polling and stories of physical attacks, sexual harassment, verbal abuse, and violence in Ontario hospitals.
Every day, frontline caregivers are suffering serious injuries that lead to time off work and even post-traumatic stress disorder. Instead of protecting their staff, hospital managers discourage them from reporting incidents and have even fired a nurse for revealing the real epidemic of violence in healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>