<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facts on CUPE Hospitals</title>
    <link>/facts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facts on CUPE Hospitals</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/facts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CUPE&#39;s Detailed Guide to PSLRTA</title>
      <link>/facts/pslrta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/pslrta/</guid>
      <description>When workplaces covered by PSLRTA amalgamate, merge or restructure, the Ontario Labour Relations Board (OLRB) will, in consultation with the affected unions and employers, determine what bargaining units are appropriate in the new workplace.
Table of Contents  What is PSLRTA? How does PSLRTA work? The Ontario Labour Relation Board&amp;rsquo;s role The PSLRTA campaign Accessing workers in other unions/workplaces What is the voting process? Life after the vote  What happens to my CA?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harmonization: What is the process?</title>
      <link>/facts/harmonization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/harmonization/</guid>
      <description>What is Harmonization? Harmonization is the process of taking the Collective Agreements from all the union’s involved in the merger, along with any non union working conditions, and merging them into the new ‘first’ Collective Agreement.
Some employers see a merger as an opportunity to table concessions to Collective Agreements or non union working conditions but CUPE negotiates to maintain superior conditions and believes that you should not lose hard won rights and benefits due to a merger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Posting and Promotion Update for newly merged hospitals</title>
      <link>/facts/post-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/post-promotion/</guid>
      <description>What should I do if I hold a position at more than one location? Nothing! The employer has advised CUPE that they will not be making any changes at this time, even if you are working more than the Full time Equivalent or max hours in the collective agreement.
Human Resources as advised all their managers of this so no one should be advised by their manager or supervisor that they need to resign from any position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPNs have a strong voice with CUPE</title>
      <link>/facts/rpn-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/rpn-info/</guid>
      <description>New infographic flyer explains why CUPE is the right union for RPNs.
Download the PDF version
CUPE bargaining sets the lead for all hospital service, RPN, and clerical workers in Ontario. Comparing our collective agreements to other unions bears this out. CUPE has superior language on seniority rights, job security, layoffs and recall, and health and safety to name but a few issues.
Did you know that?  With nearly 80,000 members employed in hospitals, long-term care, community care and paramedicine, CUPE is Ontario’s largest health care union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining a Union</title>
      <link>/facts/joining-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/joining-union/</guid>
      <description>Often during an union organizing drive workers and the employer will focus primarily on monetary issues.
Employers will often scare workers into believing that they will take home less as a result of paying union dues.
The fact is that unionized workers earn more than non union workers. That is one of the reasons why employers don&amp;rsquo;t want a union in the workplace. The other reason they don&amp;rsquo;t want a union is because they lose the absolute control they currently have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does my workplace become unionized with CUPE?</title>
      <link>/facts/how-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/how-union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A percentage of not less than 40% of the employees must sign union membership cards, then an application for certification is submitted to the Ontario Labour Relations Board.  One week later the Ontario Labour Relations Board holds a secret ballot vote at your workplace.  In order for the union to be successful fifty percent plus one of the employees who cast a ballot must vote in favour of the union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to expect from your Employer</title>
      <link>/facts/managements-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/facts/managements-message/</guid>
      <description>Management&amp;rsquo;s message A good employer will respect your right to make an informed decision about whether joining CUPE is the right choice for you and your colleagues. However, it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for employers to be afraid that you will join the Union so they resort to using union busting companies or the tactics promoted by those companies. These tactics typically take one of two directions. Either they take the &amp;lsquo;sweet talking&amp;rsquo; direction or they choose to &amp;lsquo;exploit fear of the unknown&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>